PRASHHANTH

Java | Angular 2+ | MicroServices | AWS

Backend Skills

- Java-8
- Spring Boot
- Spring Data JPA
- MicroServices
- MySql
- MongoDB

Frontend Skills

- Angular
- NextJs
- NodeJs

Other Skills

- AWS (Amazon Web Services)
- Terraform
- Jenkins
- Python
- Numpy
- Pandas
- Stoplight





About

With more power comes great responsibility

Advanced Java web and service development skills, typically built through 4+ years of applicable experience developing in Java/Spring. Professional experience developing responsive designs

and single page applications. Experience tuning and maximising performance for high volume pages. Experience participating as a member of a scrum team in an agile environment. Ability to troubleshoot environmental issues.



Experience

2018–2019 Full Stack Developer

Verizon, Hyderabad

Implemented performance tuning feature where the time complexity is reduced. Developed web pages to users to display customer data based on business requirement both in UI and backend. Integrated third party APIs like CISCO to analyse the reports and billing generated based on contract.

2019–2021 Senior Full Stack Developer

Mphasis, Hyderabad

Fetching the data from the Talend jobs which run in the background and store the data to relational database(Mysql).Implement a config Server in MicroService. Added Spring Security feature in one of the module. Understanding of software development methodologies

2021-Present Senior Consultant

Hitachi Vantara, Hyderabad

Working in a collaborative team of application developers and source code repositories. Demonstrated ability to follow through with all tasks, promises, and commitments. Communicate and work effectively within priorities. Advanced understanding of software design concepts.



Education

2017 Master of Computer Applications

Osmania University, Hyderabad

Holding a master degree with course work of programming languages like Java, C and C++. Data Engineering and Software Design along with Relational DataBases such as SQL.